Jano González

Berlin, Germany | info@janogonzalez.com | github.com/janogonzalez

Profile

Software Engineer with 15+ years experience designing, implementing and operating distributed systems that serve millions of requests per minute, mentoring engineers, leading teams of up to 7 people and presenting in events and conferences like <u>LISA</u>, <u>RubyNation</u> and <u>JRubyConf</u>.

Experience

Staff Software Engineer – Contentful

Apr 2020 – Jun 2021

 Enabled the rollout of GraphQL to thousands of customers by introducing a new tenant type

Senior Software Engineer – SoundCloud

2014 - 2020

- Secured 6 extra years without space issues in the main database cluster by extracting social graph microservices out of a Ruby on Rails monolith
- Designed and implemented microservices using Scala and JRuby, coordinated the integration with 5+ engineering teams and safely rolled out traffic to millions of users
- Improved resource utilization by 50% and enabled daily deploys by migrating the Ruby on Rails monolith from bare-metal to Kubernetes
- Identified lack of new contributors to the Ruby on Rails monolith as a risk. Mitigated the risk by introducing an ownership plan and aligning 5+ engineering teams around it
- Mentored 7 developers including colleagues and interns from the Rails Girls SoC program

CTO – Hopln 2012 – 2013

- Recruited and led a team of 5 developers to drive the transition from prototype to MVP
- Scaled the backend and infrastructure to the first thousands of users

Senior Software Engineer – Continuum

2011

Engineering Manager / Project Manager – Taisa

2008 - 2010

- Led teams of up to 7 developers
- Delivered 2FA middleware used by hundreds of thousands of customers in banks and retail

Software Engineer – Depósito Central de Valores

2005 - 2008

Software Engineer – Everis

2005

Education

Software Engineer – Universidad del Bío-Bío, Chile

2000 - 2004

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby, Scala, Go, JavaScript, SQL, Java
- Technologies: MySQL, Kafka, Cassandra, Kubernetes, AWS, Prometheus
- Other: Distributed Systems, Site Reliability Engineering, Test Driven Development